Guide to the National Education Association-Special Collections records, 1857-2015 NEA1007.RG
Special Collections Research Center, The George Washington University
- Awards, 1939-1999; 1952-1986; Series 3; 15.5 Linear Feet
  - Hilda Maehling Fellowships- Miller, Mattie S., 1981-1982; Series 3 (Box 2814, Folder 8)
  - Hilda Maehling Fellowships- Miller, Mel, 1981-1984; Series 3 (Box 2814, Folder 9)
  - Hilda Maehling Fellowships- Minutes, 1981-1982; Series 3 (Box 2814, Folder 10)
  - Hilda Maehling Fellowships- Notebooks, 1981-1982; Series 3 (Box 2814, Folder 11)
  - Hilda Maehling Fellowships- Originals, 1975; Series 3 (Box 2832, Folder 6)
  - Hilda Maehling Fellowships- Pamphlets [1/2], 1938-1970; Series 3 (Box 2832, Folder 7)
  - Hilda Maehling Fellowships- Pamphlets [2/2], 1968-1970; Series 3 (Box 2832, Folder 8)
  - Hilda Maehling Fellowships- Peterson, Donna Y., 1981; Series 3 (Box 2814, Folder 12)
  - Hilda Maehling Fellowships- Project #1 Mr. Phillip J. Hart, 1972; Series 3 (Box 2832, Folder 9)
  - Hilda Maehling Fellowships- Project #2 Mrs. Maureen C. Angelini, 1972; Series 3 (Box 2833, Folder 2)
  - Hilda Maehling Fellowships- Project #3 Mrs. Linda K. Berg, 1971-1973; Series 3 (Box 2832, Folder 10)
  - Hilda Maehling Fellowships- Publicity, 1981; Series 3 (Box 2814, Folder 13)
  - Hilda Maehling Fellowships- Ranieri, Gerome N., 1970-1971; Series 3 (Box 2814, Folder 14)
  - Hilda Maehling Fellowships- Richardson, Lowell Slater, 1970; Series 3 (Box 2814, Folder 15)
  - Hilda Maehling Fellowships- Robinson, Lithangia S., 1969-1970; Series 3 (Box 2814, Folder 16)
  - Hilda Maehling Fellowships- Royston, Judith, 1981-1982; Series 3 (Box 2815, Folder 1)
  - Hilda Maehling Fellowships- Scherr, Nancy, 1977-1978; Series 3 (Box 2815, Folder 2)
  - Hilda Maehling Fellowships- Scott, Jessie W., 1981-1982; Series 3 (Box 2815, Folder 3)
  - Hilda Maehling Fellowships- Selles, Violet Krake, 1969-1972; Series 3 (Box 2815, Folder 4)
  - Hilda Maehling Fellowships- Siddall, Elisabeth, 1970-1971; Series 3 (Box 2815, Folder 5)
  - Hilda Maehling Fellowships- Siemer, Lyle, 1977-1978; Series 3 (Box 2815, Folder 6)
  - Hilda Maehling Fellowships- Slusarski, Peg, 1977-1979; Series 3 (Box 2815, Folder 8)
  - Hilda Maehling Fellowships- Smithgall, Elizabeth, 1970; Series 3 (Box 2815, Folder 9)
  - Hilda Maehling Fellowships- Sofranac, Rodo, 1976-1978; Series 3 (Box 2815, Folder 10)
  - Hilda Maehling Fellowships- Sordahl, Lorraine, 1970; Series 3 (Box 2815, Folder 11)
  - Hilda Maehling Fellowships- Stinnett, 1971; Series 3 (Box 2833, Folder 6)
  - Hilda Maehling Fellowships- Waldo, Gary, 1977-1979; Series 3 (Box 2816, Folder 1)
  - Hilda Maehling Fellowships- Weber, Helen, 1980-1982; Series 3 (Box 2816, Folder 2)
  - Hilda Maehling Fellowships- Weisman, Jay and Rogers, Marilyn, 1980-1982; Series 3 (Box 2816, Folder 3)
  - Hilda Maehling Fellowships- White, Bill, 1981-1982; Series 3 (Box 2816, Folder 4)
  - Hilda Maehling Fellowships- Wong, Katherine and Roberts, Elizabeth, 1977-1978; Series 3 (Box 2816, Folder 5)
  - Hilda Maehling Fellowships- Wyland, John L., 1981; Series 3 (Box 2816, Folder 6)
  - Invitations - Headquarters and Affiliates, 1997-1998; Series 3 (Box 4079, Folder 8)
  - Fenner, Dr. Mildred S.- Accomplishment in Achievement of Purpose- Middle Atlantic Association of Industrial Editors, 1961; Series 3 (Box 2816, Folder 7)
  - Fenner, Dr. Mildred S.- Accomplishment in Field of Industrial Journalism- Middle Atlantic Association of Industrial Editors, 1958; Series 3 (Box 2816, Folder 8)
  - Fenner, Dr. Mildred S.- Significant Service to American Youth- Boy Scouts of America, 1960; Series 3 (Box 2816, Folder 9)
  - Fisher, James John- Magazine Covers- Awarded by Art Directors Club of Metropolitan Washington, 1957; Series 3 (Box 2816, Folder 10)
  - Fisher, James John- Art General, Two or More Colors- Art Directors Club of Metropolitan Washington, 1962; Series 3 (Box 2817, Folder 1)
  - From National War Fund, November 13, 1945; Series 3 (Box 3301, Folder 6)
  - Golden Key Award, 1962; series 3 (Box 4378, Folder 4)
  - LISTA National Latino Technology Achievers Awards, 2007 October 25; Series 3 (Box 5035, Folder 3)
  - Livingstone College, Samuel Edward Duncan Awards Banquet (Elizabeth Duncan Koontz), May 17, 1969; Series 3 (Box 4677, Folder 6)
  - Lord and Taylor Award, 1952; Series 3 (Box 3316, Folder 7)
  - National Education Association- Editorial Design- Art Directors Club of Metropolitan Washington, 1963; Series 3 (Box 2817, Folder 2)
  - National Education Association- Editorial Photography- Art Directors Club of Metropolitan Washington, 1964; Series 3 (Box 2817, Folder 3)
  - National Historic Marker Program in Commemoration of the Contribution of Teachers - Black Americans - to the Development of the United States Nation, 1978; Series 3 (Box 3303, Folder 6)
  - National Student Teacher Competition - Winners, 1982-1986; Series 3 (Box 3316, Folder 8)
  - NEA Education Support Personnel Award Recipient- Mahurin, Karen, July 6, 1997; Series 3 (Box 4623, Folder 13)
  - NEA Journal- Educational Journalism- Educational Press Association, 1964; Series 3 (Box 2817, Folder 5)
  - NEA Journal- Exceptional Service to Safety- National Safety Council, Undated; Series 3 (Box 2818, Folder 1)
  - NEA Journal- Feature Article- Educational Press Association of America, 1967; Series 3 (Box 2818, Folder 2)
  - NEA Journal- Fiftieth Anniversary- Department of Classroom Teachers, 1963; Series 3 (Box 2818, Folder 3)
  - NEA Journal- Fight Against Hunger, Disease and Ignorance Among Children in The Developing Areas of the World- UNICEF, Undated; Series 3 (Box 2818, Folder 4)
  - NEA Journal- One Million Copies- National Publishing Company, 1961; Series 3 (Box 2818, Folder 5)
  - NEA Journal- Outstanding Design Appearance- Industrial Marketing, 1957; Series 3 (Box 2818, Folder 6)
  - NEA Journal- Outstanding Graphic Presentation- Industrial Marketing, 1950; Series 3 (Box 2819, Folder 1)
  - NEA Journal- Picture Story- Educational Press Association of America, 1963; Series 3 (Box 2819, Folder 2)
  - NEA-PAC Awards, February 11, 1993; Series 3 (Box 3318, Folder 3)
  - NEA-PAC Awards - CS, October 14, 1993; Series 3 (Box 3318, Folder 4)
  - NEA Pairs with UAW/ Saturn to Award Educators and Administrators to Create Quality Schools, July 6, 1997; Series 3 (Box 4623, Folder 14)
  - NEA Reporter- Awards Editions [1/2], 1971-1972; Series 3 (Box 2819, Folder 3)
  - NEA Reporter- Awards Editions [2/2], 1972-1974; Series 3 (Box 2819, Folder 4)
  - NEA Reporter- Editorials- Educational Press Association of America, 1973; Series 3 (Box 2819, Folder 5)
  - NEA Reporter- Editorial- Educational Press Association of America, 1974; Series 3 (Box 2819, Folder 6)
  - NEA Reporter- Front Page Layout- Educational Press Association of America, 1977; Series 3 (Box 2820, Folder 1)
  - NEA Reporter- Front Page Layout- Educational Press Association of America, 1978; Series 3 (Box 2820, Folder 2)
  - NEA Reporter- Graphics- Educational Press Association of America, 1974; Series 3 (Box 2820, Folder 3)
  - NEA Reporter- Graphics- Educational Press Association of America, 1975; Series 3 (Box 2820, Folder 4)
  - NEA Reporter- Graphics- Educational Press Association of America, 1976; Series 3 (Box 2820, Folder 5)
  - NEA Reporter- Graphics- Educational Press Association of America, 1977; Series 3 (Box 2820, Folder 6)
  - NEA Reporter- Graphics- Educational Press Association of America, 1978; Series 3 (Box 2821, Folder 1)
  - NEA Reporter- Layout- Educational Press Association of America, Undated; Series 3 (Box 2821, Folder 2)
  - NEA Reporter- News Stories- Educational Press Association of America, 1972; Series 3 (Box 2821, Folder 3)
  - NEA Reporter- News Story- Educational Press Association of America, 1974; Series 3 (Box 2821, Folder 4)
  - NEA Reporter- News Story- Educational Press Association of America, Undated; Series 3 (Box 2821, Folder 5)
  - NEA Reporter- Page One- Educational Press Association of America, 1973; Series 3 (Box 2821, Folder 6)
  - NEA Reporter- Special Publication- Educational Press Association of America, 1969-1970; Series 3 (Box 2822, Folder 1)
  - NEA Reporter- One Theme Issue- Educational Press Association of America, 1975; Series 3 (Box 2822, Folder 2)
  - NEA - Thom McAn School Board Awards Program, September 1965; Series 3 (Box 4930, Folder 17)
  - NEA Thom McAn School Board Awards National Recognition, Series 3 (Box 4931, Folder 1)
  - NEA - Thom School Board Awards Program, 1965; Series 3 (Box 4930, Folder 18)
  - NEA Reporter- Typography- Educational Press Association of America, 1965; Series 3 (Box 2822, Folder 3)
  - NEA Reporter- Typography- Educational Press Association of America, 1967; Series 3 (Box 2822, Folder 4)
  - NEA Reporter- Typography- Educational Press Association of America, 1969; Series 3 (Box 2822, Folder 5)
  - NEA Reporter- Typography- Educational Press Association of America, Undated; Series 3 (Box 2822, Folder 6)
  - NEA Reporter- Typography- Educational Press Association of America, Undated; Series 3 (Box 2823, Folder 1)
  - National Teacher of the Year, April 15 1980; series 3 (Box 4502, Folder 13)
  - Paul Winfield presenting Cindy Boyd; Richard Dean Anderson presenting to Ellen Knudson; Paula Zahn & Henry Smith presenting to Gwynn Pearson, 1995; Series 3 (Box 3318, Folder 7)
  - Peacemaker Awards- Correspondence, 1966-1967; Series 3 (Box 2823, Folder 2)
  - Peacemaker Awards- Parade Magazine, June 1965; Series 3 (Box 2823, Folder 3)
  - Peacemaker Awards- Program, 1966; Series 3 (Box 2823, Folder 4)
  - Plaque "In Appreciation for Your Contribution to the Freedom Hall Campaign", undated; series 3 (Box 4378, Folder 5)
  - Plaque "For Continuing Support of, and Cooperation, with, all Endeavors for Public Education to Ensure Equity and Integration for all Youth in these United States", March 1986; series 3 (Box 4378, Folder 6)
  - Plaque "Labor Award", 1988; series 3 (Box 4378, Folder 7)
  - President's Letters to Winners, 1997; Series 3 (Box 4079, Folder 9)
  - Round-Up and Instructional Fair, award made by, April 3, 1965; Series 3 (Box 2824, Folder 1)
  - Teacher of the Year- Adams, Helen- Wisconsin, 1961; Series 3 (Box 2834, Folder 1)
  - Teacher of the Year- Barbour, Elaine- Colorado, 1978; Series 3 (Box 2834, Folder 2)
  - Teacher of the Year- Baumgartner, Andy, July 5, 1999; Series 3 (Box 4623, Folder 15)
  - Teacher of the Year- Bimes, Beverly- Missouri, 1980; Series 3 (Box 2834, Folder 3)
  - Teacher of the Year- Bizzell, Eugene Guy- Texas, 1957; Series 3 (Box 2834, Folder 4)
  - Teacher of the Year- Black, Marilyn Williams- New Hampshire, 1979; Series 3 (Box 2834, Folder 5)
  - Teacher of the Year- Brombacher, Bruce- Ohio, 1982; Series 3 (Box 2834, Folder 6)
  - Teacher of the Year- Davenport, Hazel Bragg- West Virginia, 1960; Series 3 (Box 2834, Folder 7)
  - Teacher of the Year- Dayton, Mona- Arizona, 1966; Series 3 (Box 2834, Folder 8)
  - Teacher of the Year- Dennis, Johnnie T.- Washington, 1970; Series 3 (Box 2834, Folder 9)
  - Teacher of the Year- Donley, Edna- Oklahoma, 1959; Series 3 (Box 2834, Folder 10)
  - Teacher of the Year- Draper, Sharon, July 5, 1997; Series 3 (Box 4623, Folder 16)
  - Teacher of the Year- Ensworth, John A.- Oregon, 1973; Series 3 (Box 2834, Folder 11)
  - Teacher of the Year- French, Marjorie- Kansas, 1962; Series 3 (Box 2834, Folder 12)
  - Teacher of the Year- Goleman, Barbara- Florida, 1969; Series 3 (Box 2834, Folder 13)
  - Teacher of the Year- Graf, David E.- Illinois, 1968; Series 3 (Box 2834, Folder 14)
  - Teacher of the Year- Hays, Leroy- Connecticut, 1983; Series 3 (Box 2834, Folder 16)
  - Teacher of the Year- Hamilton, Dorothy- Connecticut, 1953; Series 3 (Box 2834, Folder 15)
  - Teacher of the Year- Heyer, Robert G.- Minnesota, 1975; Series 3 (Box 2834, Folder 17)
  - Teacher of the Year- Humphry, Jean Listeberger- Iowa, 1958; Series 3 (Box 2834, Folder 18)
  - Teacher of the Year- Jones, Geraldine- California, 1952; Series 3 (Box 2834, Folder 19)
  - Teacher of the Year- Klinck, Richard E.- Colorado, 1965; Series 3 (Box 2834, Folder 20)
  - Teacher of the Year- Miscellaneous, 1952-1983; Series 3 (Box 2834, Folder 21)
  - Teacher of the Year- Murchison, Ruby S.- North Carolina, 1976; Series 3 (Box 2834, Folder 22)
  - Teacher of the Year- Nelson, Richard- Montana, 1956; Series 3 (Box 2834, Folder 23)
  - Teacher of the Year- Ousley, Elmon- Washington, 1963; Series 3 (Box 2834, Folder 24)
  - Teacher of the Year- Publications- "What and Why are the 'Teacher of the Year' Awards"- Wiese, Otis Lee, 1957; Series 3 (Box 2834, Folder 25)
  - Teacher of the Year- Rogers, James A., Jr- North Carolina, 1972; Series 3 (Box 2834, Folder 26)
  - Teacher of the Year- Sommer, Jay- New York, 1981; Series 3 (Box 2834, Folder 27)
  - Teacher of the Year- Schwarz, Mary Field- Missouri, 1957; Series 3 (Box 2834, Folder 28)
  - Teacher of the Year- Stringfellow, Martha Marion- South Carolina, 1971; Series 3 (Box 2834, Folder 29)
  - Teacher of the Year- Tenney, Roger- Minnesota, 1967; Series 3 (Box 2834, Folder 30)
  - Teacher of the Year- Teufel, Margaret Perry- Oregon, 1955; Series 3 (Box 2834, Folder 31)
  - Teacher of the Year- Tom, Vivian- New York, 1974; Series 3 (Box 2834, Folder 32)
  - Teacher of the Year- Trout, Lawana- Oklahoma, 1964; Series 3 (Box 2834, Folder 32)
  - Teacher of the Year- Widerberg, Willard- Illinois, 1954; Series 3 (Box 2834, Folder 33)
  - Television and Broadcasting Pamphlets, 1990-1993; Series 3 (Box 4079, Folder 10)
  - Today's Education- Cartoon- Educational Press Association of America, 1977; Series 3 (Box 2825, Folder 1)
  - Today's Education- Cover Design- Educational Press Association of America, 1978; Series 3 (Box 2825, Folder 2)
  - Today's Education- Cover Design- Educational Press Association of America, 1980; Series 3 (Box 2825, Folder 3)
  - Today's Education- Covers- Educational Press Association of America, 1973; Series 3 (Box 2825, Folder 4)
  - Today's Education- Feature Article- Educational Press Association of America, 1972; Series 3 (Box 2825, Folder 5)
  - Today's Education- Feature Article- Educational Press Association of America, 1973; Series 3 (Box 2825, Folder 6)
  - Today's Education- Feature Story- Educational Press Association of America, 1974; Series 3 (Box 2826, Folder 1)
  - Today's Education- Feature Story- Educational Press Association of America, 1974; Series 3 (Box 2826, Folder 2)
  - Today's Education- Feature- Educational Press Association of America, 1979; Series 3 (Box 2826, Folder 3)
  - Today's Education- Golden Lamp Award- Educational Press Association of America, 1969; Series 3 (Box 2827, Folder 1)
  - Today's Education- Graphics- Educational Press Association of America, 1972; Series 3 (Box 2826, Folder 4)
  - Today's Education- Layout- Educational Press Association of America, Undated; Series 3 (Box 2826, Folder 5)
  - Today's Education- Outstanding Contributions to Better Human Relations- National Conference of Christians and Jews, 1969; Series 3 (Box 2827, Folder 2)
  - Today's Education- Series- Educational Press Association of America, 1981; Series 3 (Box 2826, Folder 6)
  - Today's Education- Interview- Educational Press Association of America, 1978; Series 3 (Box 2828, Folder 1)
  - Today's Education- Paul C. Reed Memorial Award- Educational Press Association of America, 1973; Series 3 (Box 2828, Folder 2)
  - Today's Education- Typography- Educational Press Association of America, Undated; Series 3 (Box 2828, Folder 3)
  - Thom McAn School Board Awards Program, September 1966; Series 3 (Box 4930, Folder 16)
  - Tribute to Reg Weaver, July, 2008; Series 3 (Box 3301, Folder 7)
  - Unfinished Stories for Facilitating Decision Making in the Elementary Classroom, 1980; Series 3
  - Unfinished Stories for Facilitating Decision Making in the Elementary Classroom, 1980; Series 3 (Box 4599, Folder 7)
  - Veterans of Foreign Wars; Resolution of recognition and appreciation of NEA's development of yourth, safety and patriotic programs, 1976-1982; Series 3 (Box 3301, Folder 8)
  - William Carr Scholarships- Announcements/Articles, 1968-1975; Series 3 (Box 2828, Folder 4)
  - William Carr Scholarships- Applications and Applicant Information, 1976-1980; Series 3 (Box 2828, Folder 5)
  - William Carr Scholarships- Correspondence, 1972-1973; Series 3 (Box 2828, Folder 7)
  - William Carr Scholarships- Davidson, Margaret (Michigan), 1975-1977; Series 3 (Box 2828, Folder 8)
  - William Carr Scholarships- Financial Information [1/2], 1974-1976; Series 3 (Box 2828, Folder 9)
  - William Carr Scholarships- Financial Information [2/2], 1977-1981; Series 3 (Box 2828, Folder 10)
  - William Carr Scholarships- General Correspondence, 1975-1981; Series 3 (Box 2828, Folder 11)
  - William Carr Scholarships- Hetzer, Arnold H. (Connecticut), 1976-1978; Series 3 (Box 2830, Folder 1)
  - William Carr Scholarships- Information, Ca. 1970; Series 3 (Box 2830, Folder 2)
  - William Carr Scholarships- Initial Screening [1/3], 1971-1973; Series 3 (Box 2830, Folder 3)
  - William Carr Scholarships- Initial Screening [2/3], 1973-1974; Series 3 (Box 2830, Folder 4)
  - William Carr Scholarships- Initial Screening [3/3], 1975; Series 3 (Box 2830, Folder 5)
  - William Carr Scholarships- Intsiful, George (Ghana), 1973; Series 3 (Box 2830, Folder 6)
  - William Carr Scholarships- List of Winners from 1968-1978, Ca. 1978; Series 3 (Box 2830, Folder 7)
  - William Carr Scholarships- Meetings [1/3], 1968-1982; Series 3 (Box 2829, Folder 1)
  - William Carr Scholarships- Meetings [2/3], 1970; Series 3 (Box 2830, Folder 8)
  - William Carr Scholarships- Meetings [3/3], 1979-1981; Series 3 (Box 2829, Folder 2)
  - William Carr Scholarships- Park, Tae Kyu (Korea), 1970-1971; Series 3 (Box 2829, Folder 3)
  - William Carr Scholarships- Publicity, 1978-1980; Series 3 (Box 2829, Folder 4)
  - William Carr Scholarships- Puffer, Clark (Utah), 1976-1977; Series 3 (Box 2829, Folder 5)
  - William Carr Scholarships- Rardin, Richard (Virginia), 1979; Series 3 (Box 2829, Folder 6)
  - William Carr Scholarships- Sheretz, Wallace (Colorado), 1972-1973; Series 3 (Box 2829, Folder 7)
  - William Carr Scholarships- Simpson, Jane (New Jersey), 1979-1981; Series 3 (Box 2829, Folder 8)
  - William Carr Scholarships- McGettrick, Rosemary (New York), 1980-1982; Series 3 (Box 2829, Folder 9)
  - William Carr Scholarships- Wood, William (Wisconsin), 1974; Series 3 (Box 2829, Folder 10)
- Birmingham Education Association, 1966-1968; Series 4; 0.5 Linear Feet
  Biographical note on John Dunlop
  John Dunlop graduated from Michigan State University in 1959 with a degree in history. He was employed by the Birmingham, Michigan public school district as a high school/junio high school history/English teacher in September, 1960. He was on the faculty of Wylie E. Groves High School from 1960 to 1963 and then transferred to Berkshire Junior High School, serving on its faculty from 1963 to 1968.
  In 1966, Dunlop became active in the Birmingham Education Association serving on a contract drafting committee, then as chairman of the local greivance committee during the 1966-1967 school year. In 1967, he was elected president of the Birmingham Education Association serving in such capacity during a teachers' strike in the Fall of 1967. At that time, future NEA executive director Don Cameron was employed as executive director of the Birmingham Education Association. In addition, Walter Rogowski, future executive director of New Mexico-NEA served as vice-president of the BEA.
  In 1967, Dunlop recieved a law degree from the Detroit College of Law, passed the Michigan state bar exam and was sworn in as a lawyer licensed to practice in Michigan. At the suggestion of Don Cameron, Dunlop applied for a field services position in the NEA and was hired in August, 1968. He was assigned to the Midwest Regional Office, where Gene Preston served as regional director and Morris Andrews served as negotiation specialist. Both Preston and Andrews had been employed in Michigan, Preston as a local executive director and Andrews as a field representative of the Michigan Education Association. Preston would go on to become executive director of the Pennsylvania Education Association and Andrew would go on to become executive director of the Wisconsin Education Association.
  In 1970, Dunlop transferred to the Northwest Regional Office based in Seattle, Washington. In 1971, he was appointed chief negotiator of the Hawaii State Teachers Association. HSTA had won a representation election in early 1971 (which Dunlop took part in) and preparing to bargain a statewide collective bargaining agreement for teachers. In 1972, the HSTA conducted a strike to bring a successful conclusion to its bargaining effort.
  Dunloptransferred to NEA headquarters in 1972 to work in the Office of Negotiation, a unit of the Division of Affiliate Services. Don Conrad was manager of the Office of Negotiation and Gary Watts was head of the Division of Affiliate Services. In 1976, Dunlop was promoted to manager of the Office of Negotiation.
  As an NEA manager from 1976 to 1985, Dunlop had responsibility for two major programs (Uniserv and Leadership Development). He managed at the operational level, implementing programs established by NEA governance and higher administration, although he did influence policy decisions through the budget development process, being staff liaison to governance committees and making recommendations to higher adminstrators.
  From 1985 to 1986, Dunlop was a staff assistant at the management level to John Hein, assistant executive director for Affiliate Services. In 1986, Dunlop was made coordinator of NEA's Compensation Project. In 1990 a new division was created; the Collective Bargaining and Compensation Division. Dunlop was appointed director of the new division and had responsibility for four major programs-Compensation Project, Health Care Reform, Collective Bargaining and New Unionism. Dunlop retired after 29 years in the NEA.
  Series contains records created or collected by John Dunlop in his role first as a member and later as president of the Birmingham Education Association.
  Series is arranged alphabetically by title than chronologically after that.
  Custodial History
  The records were kept by John Dunlop after he retired from the NEA. He performed some preliminary arrangement and description of the material before it came to GWU.
  - Birmingham (MI) Education Association - Notes, n.d.; Series 4 (Box 3128, Folder 1)
  - Birmingham (MI) Education Association, September 21, 1966; Series 4 (Box 3128, Folder 2)
  - Birmingham (MI) Education Association, October 1966; Series 4 (Box 3128, Folder 3)
  - Birmingham (MI) Education Association, November 17, 1966; Series 4 (Box 3128, Folder 4)
  - Birmingham (MI) Education Association [1/4], 1966-1967; Series 4 (Box 3128, Folder 5)
  - Birmingham (MI) Education Association [2/4], 1966-1967; Series 4 (Box 3128, Folder 6)
  - Birmingham (MI) Education Association [3/4], 1966-1967; Series 4 (Box 3128, Folder 7)
  - Birmingham (MI) Education Association [4/4], 1966-1967; Series 4 (Box 3128, Folder 8)
  - Birmingham (MI) Education Association, 1966-1968; Series 4 (Box 3128, Folder 9)
  - Birmingham (MI) Education Association, February 10, 1967; Series 4 (Box 3128, Folder 10)
  - Birmingham (MI) Education Association [1/6], 1967; Series 4 (Box 3128, Folder 11)
  - Birmingham (MI) Education Association [2/6], 1967; Series 4 (Box 3128, Folder 12)
  - Birmingham (MI) Education Association [3/6], 1967; Series 4 (Box 3128, Folder 13)
  - Birmingham (MI) Education Association [4/6], 1967; Series 4 (Box 3128, Folder 14)
  - Birmingham (MI) Education Association [5/6], 1967; Series 4 (Box 3128, Folder 15)
  - Birmingham (MI) Education Association [6/6], 1967; Series 4 (Box 3128, Folder 16)